Brendan Layton

Digital Marketing Consultant at Canadian Feed The Children

brendanlayton@gmail.com

Summary

I have nine-years experience executing online marketing campaigns. I have Bachelor of Business (Marketing) and I am Google Certified in AdWords and Analytics. I specialize in working remotely for North American organizations managing their Search Marketing, Email Marketing, Social Media Marketing, Content Marketing and Website Design & Development projects. A bilingual communicator (English & Spanish), I have experience working in Europe, North America, Argentina and Australia. I live in Bariloche, Argentina. Specialties: Google AdWords (CPC, Display & Remarketing), Google Analytics, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Facebook Pages, Facebook Advertising (Promoted Posts), Twitter and YouTube Advertising, YouTube Branded Channel, Email Marketing, UI/UX Development, Website Project Management.

Experience

Online Marketing Consultant at New Internationalist

September 2011 - Present (4 years 6 months)

New Internationalist Publications is an independent cooperative that produces the award-winning magazine the New Internationalist. My role involves developing and executing a strategic online marketing plan for the North American office. The role is also heavily focused on supporting the magazine's move into the digital space. The main tasks include: • Digital Magazine Marketing: Development of recommendations for entering the digital magazine space including managing tactical tasks such as distribution selection, magazine app development and developing and executing the content marketing plan. • Online Advertising: Managing shop and subscription advertising using Google AdWords (Search, Display & Remarketing), Facebook and Twitter. • House Advertising: Managing the website's house and external advertising using doubleclick by Google. • Enewsletters: Creation and distribution of eNewsletters that promote the online shop and magazine subscriptions. • Web Development: Maintenance of the North American online shop and magazine website.

Online Marketing Consultant at Canadian Feed The Children

February 2011 - Present (5 years 1 month)

Canadian Feed The Children is a registered Canadian charity dedicated to reducing the impact of poverty on children. My role working with the charity as an Online Marketing Consultant includes: • User Experience: Using Balsamiq, I'm developing the wireframes for CFTC's website redesign project. Wireframes aim to improve the user journey, user engagement and ultimately website conversions. • Web Development & Design: I'm currently managing the design and development process for CFTC's website redesign project. Previously I managed the conversion of the client's previous website to a WordPress powered site. • Search

Engine Optimization (SEO): I am currently completing on-site and off-site optimization tasks that have already dramatically improved the site's ranking for important keywords such as "Sponsor a Child". • Online Advertising: I have liaised with representatives from Google to develop and manage Canadian Feed The Children's AdWords search and display campaigns. The campaign is currently running at a 6.90% click-through rate, with a ROI of 242%. I am also running CFTC's \$10,000/mth Google Grants account and their Facebook advertising. I am Google Adwords Certified. • Google Analytics: I have installed customized analytics code that allows tracking of users from Ad Click to Sale. I use the Experiments feature to run A/B tests, creating an environment of continuous improvement. I develop monthly reports for the client that are intuitive and include succinct analysis and next step recommendations. I am Google Analytics Certified.

Director of Online Marketing at FJ Solutions

October 2010 - September 2011 (1 year)

I worked with the talented programmers and designers at FJ Solutions to provide North American clients with affordable Web Development & Design support, including: • Website Design - Information Architecture, Website Design, Landing Page Design. • Website Development - Mobile Websites, E-Commerce Platforms, Microsites, Content Management Platforms (WordPress, Joomla, etc). • Social Media - Facebook Pages, YouTube Channels, Twitter Accounts and WordPress website integration.

Web Marketing Manager at Shepell.fgi

April 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 7 months)

This role involved developing a strategic web marketing plan for Shepell#fgi. The role also required advanced web marketing skills to manage the tactical execution of the strategic plan. Responsibilities included managing the annual web marketing budget as well as providing direction and career development to the Web Marketing Specialist.

Marketing Manager (Business & Law) at Griffith University

February 2006 - October 2007 (1 year 9 months)

Promoted to this position to market university products (degrees) to Generation Y and X in a highly competitive market. Integral components of this role included analyzing qualitative and quantitative data, developing and implementing large-scale marketing and communications campaigns and managing the annual marketing budget. The position also included managing the activities and development of the Communications Officer.

Marketing Officer at Queensland Conservatorium of Music

March 2004 - February 2006 (2 years)

Promoted to this role to develop integrated marketing campaigns positioning Queensland Conservatorium as one of the premier music institutions in Australia. Achieved this by developing and implementing event marketing campaigns, redesigning the website, developing marketing collateral and working with industry partners on mutually beneficial partnership agreements. The position also included writing media releases to set deadlines, ensuring the adherence of the corporate brand, and managing the annual marketing budget.

Skills & Expertise

PPC

SEO

Website Project Management

Google Adwords

Google Analytics

Copywriting

Online User Experience

Information Architecture

Online Advertising

Outdoor Advertising

Radio Advertising

Cinema Advertising

Television Advertising

Marketing Strategy

Digital Marketing

Online Marketing

Media Planning

Content Management

HTML

Social Media Marketing

Spanish

Facebook Advertising

Email Marketing

SEO copywriting

Project Management

Facebook

Website Development

Social Media

WordPress

Integrated Marketing

Web Design

User Experience

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Spanish (Professional working proficiency)

Certifications

Google AdWords Qualified - Search Advertising

Google License 00557049 March 2011 to March 2014

 $\label{lem:coogle} \textbf{Google AdWords Qualified - Reporting and Analysis}$

Google License 00557056 March 2011 to March 2014

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

Google License 01589003 March 2013 to September 2014

Google AdWords Qualified - Search Advertising

Google December 2015 to December 2016

Education

Queensland University of Technology

Bachelor of Business, Marketing Major, 1996 - 1998

John Paul College

High School Diploma, 1991 - 1995

Brendan Layton

Digital Marketing Consultant at Canadian Feed The Children

brendanlayton@gmail.com



2 person has recommended Brendan

"Brendan was a huge help to us at Maryland Family Network. Our organization received a Google Grant and we earned the opportunity to run AdWords to promote our organization and the work that we do. Brendan lent us his incredibly valuable services to help us make sense of how to build and run AdWord campaigns. He quickly and thoroughly explored our online presence and sent us a comprehensive evaluation of how we were presenting ourselves online, how we would be able to use AdWords to gain more attention, and things that we were going to need to work on in the future. Brendan provided valued insight about ways that we could work on our website to build a better foundation for the online work we do everywhere else. He also of course got our Google Grant in motion. He built AdWord campaigns that are logically organized and soundly built. This is very valuable to our organization. He was an enormous help to Maryland Family Network and we were very grateful to have his help!"

— Nathan McNamara, was Brendan's client

"I've worked with Brendan in a corporate environment as well as in his consulting role. In both cases, I've been truly appreciative of, first, his skill and expertise, and second, his conceptual and yet practical approach to implementing online strategies that achieve clear and measurable results. Brendan offers well-grounded, evidence-based rationale for activities and campaigns, and is able to articulate them to gain buy-in at senior levels -- especially among those who may not be as e-savvy. I particularly value his ability to forecast and suggest forward-thinking remedies and strategies to support changing organizational goals -- to think on the fly of tactics while always keeping the bigger picture business strategy in mind. This kind of initiative and insight -- especially in areas like SEO, e-marketing and social media which are constantly evolving -- is invaluable. I trust and respect his judgment. He is a true 'online partner' whom I would not hesitate to recommend to others. Plus, he's great fun, with a quick wit and a down-to-earth style, all of which make him a pleasure to work with!"

— **Jennifer Watson**, managed Brendan at Canadian Feed The Children

Contact Brendan on LinkedIn